DAVID BARON

Toronto, ON

Phone: (905) 999-0683 | Email: dcpb777@gmail.com LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/david-baron-714370226/ GitHub: github.com/HORSESH0E

Portfolio: https://github.com/HORSESH0E/DavidsPortfolioRepo

SUMMARY

Web Developer with background in scientific data collection and technical installation. Committed to accuracy and detail. As both a manager and technician, practiced process implementation, development, documentation, and been responsible for training and evaluation. Experienced in prioritizing tasks and communicating salient information accommodating multiple perspectives and initiating innovative progression, and recently earned a Certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Toronto.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, ReactJS, Handlebars.js

Back-End: Node.js, Express.js, MySQL, Sequelize ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, Insomnia

Concepts: APIs, REST, MVC, TDD, JSON, XML

Tools: Git, Github, GitLab, Firebase, Heroku, JawsDB, VS Code5

Certifications: Site Master Line Sweep Certification - Anritsu, The Art of Encouragement - Ontario Society of

Adlerian Psychology

PROJECTS

Movie Music Magic | https://github.com/HORSESH0E/movieMusicMagic | https://hOrsesh0e.github.io/movieMusicMagic/

- Helps users avoid distractions when they wish to find high-quality and moving music appropriate for study, meditation or work.
- Built and maintained team morale through conceptual development to project completion. Consulted with each team member and coded in every area of the project
- Git, GitHub, Trello, Slack, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Glide | https://github.com/HORSESH0E/glide-activity-carpooling | https://glide-activity-carpooling.herokuapp.com/

- Connects users of similar interests with each other so they can enjoy distant activities for a fraction of the travel costs
- Lead the team through brainstorming and worked on every aspect of the project to bring it to completion
- Git, GitHub, Node.js, Express.js, Express-Session, Sequelize, Sequelize-Connect-Session, MySQL2, Dotenv, Bcrypt, JawsDB Add-On, @Faker, Trello, Slack, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Pet Alert | https://github.com/KennWg/pet-finder | https://aqueous-tor-23936.herokuapp.com/

- Allows communities to efficiently cooperate to keep their pets safe by enrolling them in a light-weight and intuitive application
- The simple and straight-forward user experience promotes participation by requiring only the minimum vital information
- React, JavaScript, MongoDb, GraphQL, JWT, Trello, Slack, CSS, HTML

EXPERIENCE

Property Development - Self-Employed DBR Development

2021 – present Arden, ON

Designing and building remote recreation properties providing families with a turn-key nature-adventure experience that is unforgettable for children and an actual vacation for parents. Utilizing experience in hospitality, real estate, teaching, carpentry and design.

Key Accomplishments:

- Located real-estate, negotiated purchase, found training, acquired licenses/permits, sourced vehicles, provisioned materials, equipment and supplies: project cost \$45,000.
- Created and implemented the custom construction processes required for material handling and fabrication on-site.
- In one season, single-handedly cleared land, erected a large material/work shelter, purpose-built a large dock, and two-storey bunkie on a water-access-only property.

Renovation / Handyman Carpenter - Self-Employed Handyman Solutions

2011 - 2019

Toronto, ON

Consulted with clients, prepared estimates, sourced materials and completed various projects involving concrete work, rough carpentry, roofing, plumbing, electrical, HVAC, dry wall, finish carpentry. Utilized communication, negotiation, critical thinking and persuasive skills to build trust and rapport with clients providing safe and cost-effective solutions.

Key Accomplishments:

• Built a business based entirely on word-of-mouth by under-promising and over delivering leveraging my attention to detail..

Telecommunications Contractor/ Installer / Power Technician - Employee Wesbell

2008 - 2011

Mississauga, ON

Responsible for telecom equipment installation according to client specifications in a collaborative setting, quality assurance and control, reporting of site status and on-going refinement of installation process. Key Accomplishments:

- With no formal training, recognized for my high quality of complex installations, surpassing client requirements within tight timelines
- For Ericsson/DAVE Wireless, formulated SOP document for labeling and information tracking on all installations the SOP was adopted by all other service providers.
- (DAVE became Wind Mobile.)

Board Member - Volunteer Scarborough Music Theatre

2008 - 2009

Scarborough, ON

Responsible for branding, marketing material design, re-design and maintenance of website and ticketing research essential to the business of the overall company and its three affiliated theatre groups. Key Accomplishments:

- Received the groups' 'Randy Leslie' award for making an outstanding contribution to the company.
- Modernized the website through self-directed learning of Adobe Dreamweaver 3, raised traffic more than 300%, attained third position in Google search, previously ranked 70th.
- Investigated various ticketing companies, interviewed different service providers and their existing clients. Recommend the ticketing agent ultimately chosen.

EDUCATION

Full Stack Boot Camp Certificate: University of Toronto, Toronto, ON Registered Real Estate Representative: OREA, Vaughan, ON

Certificate of Qualification & Registration: Ontario College of Teachers, Toronto, ON

Primary / Junior Education Program: Canisius College, Buffalo, NY

Bachelor of Arts - Humanities: York University, Toronto, ON